Alex: I'm Alex.
I am a scrum master.
I have been in the role
for about six years.
Definitely done a lot of learning
on the job as well as formal
qualification six years ago.
But yeah, I'm just, I'm passionate
about agile and agile development
and continuous learning.
I used to work in marketing, I also
came from a kind of traditional
project management background.
So did that for a number of
years, but really adapting to
change, which is the only constant
really I've found in life so far.
It's bringing in more of that kind
of teamwork and collaboration and the
kind of servant leadership element
of it and protection of the team.
I feel that that kind of really
fits my, my purpose in life.
And I'm quite big on kind of
the meaning of names as well.
And my name Alex actually means
protector or defender of mankind.
So I think that that fits quite
nicely within my role as a scrum
master and servant leader as well.
I think the main purpose of a scrum
master is really being responsible
for ensuring that the team lives the
agile values and also kind of following
the scrum process kind of being the
protector of the team in that respect
and removing obstacles and blockers, and
really just establishing an effective
working environment for the team as well.
And, yeah, just doing everything
that you can to make the team's life
easier in order for them to be able to
deliver the work that needs to be done.
I mean, scrum is obviously a kind of
iterative product focused development,
where you only commit to the work that the
team plans to deliver within one sprint,
which is up to a maximum of four weeks.
As I said, previously, I came from a
kind of traditional project management
background and kind of comparing that
way of working to the traditional
waterfall way where you're kind of
planning out the entire delivery from
start to finish when inevitably things
are going to change and you're going to
come up against unknowns, not necessarily
knowing the full requirements for a
project, planning that, you know, from
start to finish at the beginning, just
doesn't really make much sense to me.
And I think that's why agile works so
well is that you're kind of chunking it
down, just focusing on the short term
and then really getting that kind of
iterative development and feedback loops.
So you're getting that fast feedback
throughout the process from the
stakeholders, from the end user, ideally
to then develop the product even further.
Absolutely being the kind of servant
leader for the team and really
kind of protecting the product
team ... To enable them to focus
primarily on delivering the product.
Helping to remove any blockers.
Managing expectations with the key
stakeholders and working with the
product owner to develop the backlog
and ensure that all of the stories
and requirements are sprint ready
in order to hand them over for the
team to then commit to the work and
deliver on those key requirements.
But yeah, really kind of having
that clear structure and being
that owner of the process really,
and yeah, protecting the team.
I think scrum is really effective
in product development in
general, whether that be software
development in the digital arena.
Definitely where a team is kind of
all working towards the same goal.
And where a team is really looking to
kind of learn through their experiences
and to continually improve their process
together with that kind of collaboration.
So as long as you've got a collaborative
team, that's kind of working towards
the same goal, then ultimately,
hopefully scrum will work for you.
I think on the flip side of that,
definitely without a self organising
team or in a team that has no autonomy
in terms of over their product delivery,
that's where it's likely to fall down.
I think it's really important
to have a team that can...
that can deliver the end to end
product and is able to have that
kind of autonomy and ownership of the
product in order for them to deliver
the best product, ultimately, really.
So yeah, without a self-organising team
it, yeah, it it's likely not to work.
I think just going back to that, to being
that protector of the team you know having
that clear structure, being the owner
of the process and just making sure that
we've got the right working environment
for the team in order for them to do their
job properly, removing any blockers, any
issues and you know, that kind of full
collaboration with the team, with the
product owner, with the key stakeholders,
making sure that you're kind of managing
everyone's expectations and that you'v
e got that clear pathway for the team
to be able to do their job effectively.